The power of one
Bilal: A New Breed of Hero is a animation, action,
adventure film directed by Ayman Jamal.
A thousand years ago, one boy with a dream of becoming a great warrior is
abducted with his sister and taken to a land far away from home.
Thrown into a world where greed and injustice rule all, Bilal finds
the courage to raise his voice and make a change.
Inspired by true events, this is a story of a real hero who
earned his remembrance in time and history.
Bilal (voice), played by Adewale Akinnuoye-Agbaje.
Ghufaira (Teen) (voice), played by China Anne McClain.
Umayya (voice), played by Ian McShane.
Bilal (Teen) (voice), played by Jacob Latimore.
Ghufaira / Hamama (voice), played by Cynthia Kaye McWilliams.
Charlatan Priest (voice), played by Fred Tatasciore.
Bilal: A New Breed of Hero is a 2015 English-language Emirati 3D animated action-adventure film about
the birth of Islam, produced by Barajoun Entertainment and co-directed by Khurram H.
Alavi and Ayman Jamal.
With a story by Jamal, the screenplay was written by Alavi,
Alex Kronemer, Michael Wolfe and Yassin Kamel.
With this film, Jamal aimed to depict heroes from
the history of the Arabian Peninsula.
The film depicts the life of Bilal ibn Rabah, who, known for his beautiful voice, was
freed from slavery and rose to a position of prominence in 632 AD.
The voice cast features Adewale Akinnuoye-Agbaje, Ian McShane, China Anne McClain, Jacob
Latimore, Thomas Ian Nicholas, Fred Tatasciore, Cynthia McWilliams, Jon Curry, Dave B.
Mitchell and Michael Gross.
Bilal premiered on December 9, 2015, at the 12th
Annual International Dubai Film Festival.
Starting September 8, 2016, the film released throughout the MENA region.
The film began an international rollout in February 2018.
Bilal won "Best Inspiring Movie" on Animation Day
at the 2016 Cannes Film Festival.
It won "Best Innovative Movie" at the BroadCast Pro Middle East Award 2016.
Bilal was nominated for Best Animated Feature Film at the 2016 Asia
Pacific Screen Awards, the region's highest accolade for film.
The film explores themes of hero, dreams, legend, freedom, greed.